Discover a world beyond your imagination.
Epic is a animation, adventure, family film directed by Chris Wedge.
A teenager finds herself transported to a deep forest setting where a battle
between the forces of good and the forces of evil is taking place.
She bands together with a rag-tag group characters in
order to save their world—and ours.
Ronin (voice), played by Colin Farrell.
Mary Katherine (M.K.) (voice), played by Amanda Seyfried.
Mandrake (voice), played by Christoph Waltz.
Nod (voice), played by Josh Hutcherson.
Bomba (voice), played by Jason Sudeikis.
Mub (voice), played by Aziz Ansari.
Epic (stylized as epic) is a 2013 American animated fantasy action-adventure film loosely based
on William Joyce's 1996 children's book The Leaf Men and the Brave Good Bugs.
Produced by Blue Sky Studios in association with 20th Century Fox Animation, it was
directed by Chris Wedge from a screenplay written by Joyce, James V.
Hart, Daniel Shere, and the writing team of Tom J.
Astle and Matt Ember, based on a story conceived by Joyce, Hart, and Wedge.
It stars the voices of Colin Farrell, Josh Hutcherson, Amanda Seyfried, Christoph Waltz, Aziz
Ansari, Chris O'Dowd, Pitbull, Jason Sudeikis, Steven Tyler, and Beyoncé Knowles.
In the film, after teenager Mary Katherine gets shrunk and teleported to a tiny woodland kingdom inhabited by talking slugs, flower people and tiny soldiers called
Leafmen, she is swept up in a wild adventure between good and evil and, alongside her new friends, must fight to protect the world she never knew existed.
Epic was internationally released on May 16, 2013, and in the United States on May 24, by
20th Century Fox, following in its premiere on Ziegfeld Theatre on May 18.
The film received generally mixed to positive reviews from critics and was a moderate
box-office success, grossing $268 million against its $93 million budget.
The film explores themes of daughter, villain, father, forest, nature.
The tone is thought_provoking.